# James Aduke

I am a web developer who is competent in both backend and frontend technologies. I know how to make the User Experience and User Interface both functional and usable by target users. I would also make the site usable to the target users. I also have an understanding of the backend from having worked with database systems such as PostgreSQL and MySQL and also frameworks such as Laravel(PHP) and Rails(Ruby)

+254720655526 https://github.com/jamesaduk

jamesaduke@outlook.com

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Eldohub, Eldoret — Junior Tech Professional

JANUARY 2021 - PRESENT

• Participated in the Thunderbird School of Global Management Leadership Course where leadership skills such as Time management, communication, Impact as a leader were taught and tested

## Tumaini Innovation Center, Eldoret — Web Developer

JANUARY 2021 - PRESENT

- Creating new features and functionality using WordPress, PHP and CSS
- Recommending and implementing UI design on the Company Website
- Developing the e-commerce platform using WordPress, PHP and M-pesa integration.

### **Tech Savanna** Technology, Nairobi — Software Developer Intern

JUNE 2019 - AUGUST 2019

- Fixing bugs and adding features to web and offline systems using PHP and Yii framework.
- Implementing user experience features to the various sites using React(Javascript) and CSS
- Collaborating on implementation of database systems using MySQL

#### **SKILLS**

HTML, CSS,

JavaScript, React

Python

Ruby on Rails

Agile Methodology

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

Microsoft Certified Azure
Fundamentals: Earners of
the Azure Fundamentals
certification have
demonstrated foundational
level knowledge of cloud
services and how those
services are provided with
Microsoft Azure

#### **LANGUAGES**

English, Kiswahili

#### **EDUCATION**

# Meru University Science and Technology, Meru — BSc. Computer Science (Degree in Progress)

September 2016 - APRIL 2021

- I was involved in various tech communities specifically Meru University Science and Innovation Club and Meru University Google Student Developer Groups
- Participated in hackathons such as the Dedan Kimathi of Science and Technology
- Learnt Object-Oriented Design and Programming

# Thurdibuoro High School — KCSE Diploma (B+)

2012-2015

• Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education